APRIL YANG

415-319-4675

aprilyang12@gmail.com

Education

Human Computer Interaction, M.S. candidate, Iowa State University, U.S. Anticipated completion: December 2021

English, B.A., Jiangsu University of Technology, China

Technical Skills

Mixed Methods

User Interview

Usability Testing

Contextual Inquiry

Heuristic Evaluation

Personas

User Story Mapping

Metric Analysis

Survey Design

SQL

Figma

Highlights

Apple Excellence Award Winner 2019

Diversity and Inclusion Team Leader

Profile

A dedicated professional with 4 years of combined experience in the research and technology fields, a highly effective self-starter with fearless curiosity and a passion to make user-centered products. Bilingual in Mandarin and English with native fluency.

Experience

Product Insights, Apple Inc.; Elk Grove, CA — 06/2018—01/2021

- Worked directly with end customers to uncover product issues, user pain points, user behavior and how people use Apple products.
- Shared insights and data with product and engineering, drove design changes and product development.

User Researcher, Apple Inc.; Cupertino, CA — 06/2020—11/2020 (Rotation)

- Worked cross-functionally with engineering and product teams, identified user study goals and designed research plans.
- Ran user research studies taking the mixed methods approach to uncover user behavior and user experience. Improved features by turning findings into product insights and sharing with leadership and teams.
- Worked with analytics data and metrics to track the performance of feature solutions, uncovered findings that led to bigger investigations.

Project Manager, Apple Inc.; Elk Grove, CA — 05/2019—08/2019 (Rotation)

- Conducted the strategic user research to uncover user experience and unfulfilled needs. Interviewed key stakeholders. Synthesized findings to influence the product development priority and strategy.
- Worked cross-functionally with engineering and business teams; led through multiple phases of projects while adopting the Agile Methodologies.

WW Apple Product Verification, Apple Inc.; Elk Grove, CA — 01/2017—05/2018

 Analyzed emerging issues from multiple regional markets, made informed decisions to protect customers and improve customer experience.